const quizQuestions = [

    
  {
  
    question: "Which of the following is the core of an operating system?",

    options: ["Shell","Kernel","Command interpreter","Scheduler"],

    correctAnswer: "Kernel"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which operating system does not support multitasking?",

    options: ["Windows","Unix","MS-DOS","Linux"],

    correctAnswer: "MS-DOS"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not an operating system?",

    options: ["Windows","Linux","Oracle","DOS"],

    correctAnswer: "Oracle"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which scheduling algorithm is best suited for a time-shared operating system?",

    options: ["First-Come-First-Served (FCFS)","Shortest Job Next (SJN)","Round Robin","Priority Scheduling"],

    correctAnswer: "Round Robin"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not a type of computer virus?",

    options: ["Boot sector","File infector","Trojan horse","Macro virus"],

    correctAnswer: "Trojan horse"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is used to manage the hardware and software resources of a computer?",

    options: ["Operating System","Compiler","Interpreter","Assembler"],

    correctAnswer: "Operating System"

  },

  
  {

    question: "What is a semaphore in operating system terms?",

    options: ["A memory management technique","A synchronization tool","A scheduling algorithm","A type of hardware"],

    correctAnswer: "A synchronization tool"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a real-time operating system?",

    options: ["Windows 10","Unix","Linux","VxWorks"],

    correctAnswer: "VxWorks"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which scheduling algorithm allocates the CPU first to the process that requests the CPU first?",

    options: ["FCFS scheduling","Round robin scheduling","Priority scheduling","Multilevel queue scheduling"],

    correctAnswer: "FCFS scheduling"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which command is used to create a directory in DOS?",

    options: ["MD","CD","RD","DIR"],

    correctAnswer: "MD"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following file systems does Windows 10 use by default?",

    options: ["NTFS","FAT32","exFAT","HFS+"],

    correctAnswer: "NTFS"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which operating system is developed by Apple?",

    options: ["Windows","Android","iOS","Linux"],

    correctAnswer: "iOS"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a command interpreter in Unix/Linux operating systems?",

    options: ["Shell","Kernel","Kernel","Compiler"],

    correctAnswer: "Shell"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not a function of the operating system?",

    options: ["Memory management","Virus protection","Process management","File management"],

    correctAnswer: "Virus protection"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a real-time operating system?",

    options: ["Windows 10","Unix","RTOS","MacOS"],

    correctAnswer: "RTOS"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not an example of a utility program?",

    options: ["Disk Cleanup","Disk Defragmenter","Windows Explorer","MS Paint"],

    correctAnswer: "MS Paint"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which memory allocation scheme suffers from external fragmentation?",

    options: ["Paging","Segmentation","Contiguous Allocation","Virtual Memory"],

    correctAnswer: "Contiguous Allocation"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not an essential property of time-sharing systems?",

    options: ["Interactivity","Response Time","Batch Processing","Multitasking"],

    correctAnswer: "Batch Processing"

  },


  
  {

    question: "In UNIX, which command is used to change the permission of files and directories?",

    options: ["chdir","chmod","chperm","chper"],

    correctAnswer: "chmod"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a non-preemptive scheduling algorithm?",

    options: ["Round Robin","Shortest Job Next","Priority Scheduling","First-Come-First-Served (FCFS)"],

    correctAnswer: "First-Come-First-Served (FCFS)"

  },


  
  {

    question: "What is the purpose of the 'nice' command in UNIX?",

    options: ["Change file permissions","Change the priority of a process","Display system information","Terminate a process"],

    correctAnswer: "Change the priority of a process"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is used to protect critical sections in a multi-threading environment?",

    options: ["Semaphore","Virtual Memory","File System","Compiler"],

    correctAnswer: "Semaphore"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which file system is designed for Linux systems?",

    options: ["NTFS","FAT32","ext4","HFS+"],

    correctAnswer: "ext4"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix, what does the 'grep' command do?",

    options: ["Change directory","Search for text patterns","Display process status","Create a new file"],

    correctAnswer: "Search for text patterns"

  },


  
  {

    question: "What is the command used to remove a directory in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["rmdir","deldir","removedir","rm"],

    correctAnswer: "rmdir"

  },


  
  {

    question: "What is the role of the 'mkfs' command in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["Create a new directory","Format a filesystem","Display file content","Mount a filesystem"],

    correctAnswer: "Format a filesystem"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following algorithms is used for memory allocation in operating systems?",

    options: ["LIFO","FIFO","Best Fit","Shortest Remaining Time"],

    correctAnswer: "Best Fit"

  },

  
  {

    question: "What is the primary job of the operating system's kernel?",

    options: ["User Interface","Resource Management","Application Development","Web Browsing"],

    correctAnswer: "Resource Management"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix, which command is used to display the currently running processes?",

    options: ["Is","ps","chmod","rm"],

    correctAnswer: "ps"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is used to increase security by separating processes on a system?",

    options: ["Sandbox","Compiler","Scheduler","Thread"],

    correctAnswer: "Sandbox"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which command is used to list the contents of a directory in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["list","Is","dir","show"],

    correctAnswer: "Is"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix/Linux, which command is used to display the contents of a file?",

    options: ["view","see","show","cat"],

    correctAnswer: "cat"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not an example of an operating system?",

    options: ["Ubuntu","Red Hat","MySQL","Solaris"],

    correctAnswer: "MySQL"

  },


  
  {

    question: "What is the primary purpose of the 'kill' command in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["Restart the system","Terminate a process","Remove a file","Format a disk"],

    correctAnswer: "Terminate a process"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a disk scheduling algorithm?",

    options: ["FCFS","SSTF","LOOK","ALL OF THE ABOVE"],

    correctAnswer: "ALL OF THE ABOVE"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which command is used to change the owner of a file in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["chown","chmod","chperm","chgrp"],

    correctAnswer: "chown"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a valid process state?",

    options: ["Running","Ready","Waiting","All of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "All of the above"

  },


  
  {

    question: "In a Unix/Linux environment, which command is used to display the manual of a command?",

    options: ["man","help","info","manual"],

    correctAnswer: "man"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not a valid file permission in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["Read","Write","Execute","Open"],

    correctAnswer: "Open"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix/Linux, what does the command 'pwd' stand for?",

    options: ["Print working directory","password change","print word document","private working directory"],

    correctAnswer: "Print working directory"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is an example of a distributed operating system?",

    options: ["Windows 7","Ubuntu","Linux","Amoeba"],

    correctAnswer: "Amoeba"

  },


  
  {

    question: "What is the primary function of a bootloader in an operating system?",

    options: ["Manage memory","load the operating system kernel","Provide security","Handle file"],

    correctAnswer: "load the operating system kernel"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is an example of a multi-tasking operating system?",

    options: ["MS-DOC","Windows","CP/M","None of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "Windows"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which file system is used by macOS?",

    options: ["NTFS","ext4","HFS+","FAT32"],

    correctAnswer: "HFS+"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix/Linux, which command is used to count the number of lines, words, and characters in a file?",

    options: ["count","wc","grep","Is"],

    correctAnswer: "wc"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a non-preemptive scheduling algorithm?",

    options: ["FCFS","Round Robin","Shortest Job First","Priority Scheduling"],

    correctAnswer: "FCFS"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which type of operating system is designed to respond to events within a predictable time frame?",

    options: ["Batch processing system","Real-time system","Multi-user system","Distributed system"],

    correctAnswer: "Real-time system"

  },

  
  {

    question: "What is the maximum length of a filename in DOS?",

    options: ["255 characters","127 characters","8 characters","64 characters"],

    correctAnswer: "8 characters"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which command in Unix/Linux is used to display the directory structure in a tree-like format?",

    options: ["ls -l","tree","list","dir"],

    correctAnswer: "tree"

  },


  
  {

    question: "What is the main function of the command cd in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["Create a new directory","Change the current directory","Copy files","Delete a directory"],

    correctAnswer: "Change the current directory"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a common shell used in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["CMD","PowerShell","Bash","None ofthe mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "Bash"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following provides the interface between the user and the hardware in a computer system?",

    options: ["Application software","Operating system","BIOS","Device drivers"],

    correctAnswer: "Operating system"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which scheduling algorithm assigns the CPU to the process with the smallest next CPU burst?",

    options: ["FCFS","Round Robin","SJF (Shortest Job First)","Priority Scheduling"],

    correctAnswer: "SJF (Shortest Job First)"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which command is used to create a new user in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["newuser","adduser","useradd","createuser"],

    correctAnswer: "useradd"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix/Linux, which command is used to display system information?",

    options: ["uname","sysinfo","info","system"],

    correctAnswer: "uname"

  },

  
  {

    question: "What is the function of the mv command in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["copy files","move or rename files","delete files","display files"],

    correctAnswer: "move or rename files"

  },

  
  {

    question: "In Unix/Linux, which command is used to search for files and directories?",

    options: ["locate","search","find","lookup"],

    correctAnswer: "find"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which command in Unix/Linux is used to display the first few lines of a file?",

    options: ["head","top","tail","start"],

    correctAnswer: "head"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a type of operating system that allows multiple users to access a computer system concurrently?",

    options: ["Single-user system","Multi-user system","Batch processing system","Real-time system"],

    correctAnswer: "Multi-user system"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which Unix/Linux command is used to change the password of a user?",

    options: ["chpwd","passwd","changepwd","setpwd"],

    correctAnswer: "passwd"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a valid state for a process in an operating system?",

    options: ["Running","Blocked","Ready","All of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "All of the mentioned"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not a common file attribute in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["Read-only","Hidden","Executable","Archive"],

    correctAnswer: "Archive"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which command is used to display the last few lines of a file in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["head","top","tail","end"],

    correctAnswer: "tail"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which Unix/Linux command is used to display the calendar?",

    options: ["time","cal","date","clock"],

    correctAnswer: "cal"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is an example of a command used to display the status of the network interfaces in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["netstat","ifconfig","ipconfig","nslookup"],

    correctAnswer: "ifconfig"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which type of operating system is best suited for use in a real-time application?",

    options: ["General-purpose OS","Real-time OS","Batch OS","Distributed OS"],

    correctAnswer: "Real-time OS"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which command is used to display the last logged-in users in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["lastlog","who","last","log"],

    correctAnswer: "last"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following commands is used to terminate a process in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["kill","end","stop","terminate"],

    correctAnswer: "kill"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following commands in Unix/Linux is used to compress files?",

    options: ["zip","tar","gzip","compress"],

    correctAnswer: "gzip"

  },

  
  {

    question: "What does the ps command in Unix/Linux display?",

    options: ["File system status","Memory usage","Running processes","network configuration"],

    correctAnswer: "Running processes"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is used to manage the boot process of a computer?",

    options: ["Bootloader","Compiler","Kernel","File System"],

    correctAnswer: "Bootloader"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which type of operating system is designed to manage multiple computers on a network?",

    options: ["real-time OS","batch OS","distributed OS","single-user OS"],

    correctAnswer: "distributed OS"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which Unix/Linux command is used to change the file ownership?",

    options: ["chmod","chown","chgrp","chperm"],

    correctAnswer: "chown"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which file system is specifically designed for flash drives?",

    options: ["FAT32","NTFS","ext3","exFAT"],

    correctAnswer: "exFAT"

  },

  
  {

    question: "What is the purpose of the clear command in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["clear the screen","clear the memory","clear the disk space","clear the cache"],

    correctAnswer: "clear the screen"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a technique for managing memory in an operating system?",

    options: ["Paging","Scheduling","Buffering","Caching"],

    correctAnswer: "Paging"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a common method for inter-process communication (IPC)?",

    options: ["Pipes","Shared Memory","Message Queues","All of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "All of the above"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following commands is used to create a new directory in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["mkdir","newdir","createdir","dircreate"],

    correctAnswer: "mkdir"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which Unix/Linux command is used to change the group ownership of a file?",

    options: ["chgrp","chmod","chown","changegrp"],

    correctAnswer: "chgrp"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a system call used for process creation in Unix/Linux?",

    options: ["exec()","fork()","wait()","exit()"],

    correctAnswer: "fork()"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a mechanism to handle deadlocks in an operating system?",

    options: ["Deadlock detection","Deadlock prevention","Deadlock avoidance","all of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "all of the above"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is a type of hypervisor used in virtualization?",

    options: ["Type 1 (bare-metal)","Type 2 (hosted)","Both","None"],

    correctAnswer: "Both"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which of the following is not a deadlock prevention technique?",

    options: ["Mutual Exclusion","Hold and Wait","Preemption","Circular Wait"],

    correctAnswer: "Hold and Wait"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which command in Unix/Linux can be used to compare the contents of two files?",

    options: ["cmp","compare","diff","cmp and compare"],

    correctAnswer: "cmp and compare"

  },


  
  {

    question: "To access the services of the operating system, the interface is provided by the ___________",

    options: ["Library","System calls","assembly instructions","API"],

    correctAnswer: "System calls"

  },


  
  {

    question: "If a process fails, most operating system write the error information to a ______",

    options: ["new file","another running process","log file","none of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "log file"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which one of the following is not a real time operating system?",

    options: ["RTLinux","Palm OS","QNX","VxWorks"],

    correctAnswer: "Palm OS"

  },


  
  {

    question: "In a timeshare operating system, when the time slot assigned to a process is completed, the process switches from the current state to?",

    options: ["Suspended state","Terminated state","Ready state","Blocked state"],

    correctAnswer: "Ready state"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Cascading termination refers to the termination of all child processes if the parent process terminates ______",

    options: ["Normally or abnormally","Abnormally","Normally","None"],

    correctAnswer: "Normally or abnormally"

  },

  
  {

    question: "The FCFS algorithm is particularly troublesome for ____________",

    options: ["operating systems","multiprocessor systems","time sharing systems","multiprogramming systems"],

    correctAnswer: "time sharing systems"

  },


  
  {

    question: "A deadlock avoidance algorithm dynamically examines the __________ to ensure that a circular wait condition can never exist.",

    options: ["operating system","resources","system storage state","resource allocation state"],

    correctAnswer: "resource allocation state"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Swapping _______ be done when a process has pending I/O, or has to execute I/O operations only into operating system buffers.",

    options: ["must never","maybe","can","must"],

    correctAnswer: "must never"

  },

  
  {

    question: "The main memory accommodates ____________",

    options: ["cpu","user processes","operating system","all of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "operating system"

  },

  
  {

    question: "The operating system is responsible for?",

    options: ["bad-block recovery","booting from disk","booting from disk","all of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "all of the mentioned"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Using transient code, _______ the size of the operating system during program execution.",

    options: ["maintains","changes","increases","decreases"],

    correctAnswer: "changes"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Hard real time operating system has ______________ jitter than a soft real time operating system.",

    options: ["equal","more","less","none of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "less"

  },


  
  {

    question: "For real time operating systems, interrupt latency should be ____________",

    options: ["zero","minimal","maximum","dependent on the scheduling"],

    correctAnswer: "minimal"

  },


  
  {

    question: "For real time operating systems, interrupt latency should be ____________",

    options: ["operating system","separate directory structure","swap space","none of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "separate directory structure"

  },

  
  {

    question: " The operating system keeps a small table containing information about all open files called ____________",

    options: ["file table","directory table","open-file table","system table"],

    correctAnswer: "open-file table"

  },

  
  {

    question: "The operating system _______ the links when traversing directory trees, to preserve the acyclic structure of the system.",

    options: ["deletes","considers","ignores","none of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "ignores"

  },

  
  {

    question: "To recover from failures in the network operations _____________ information may be maintained.",

    options: ["operating system","IP address","stateless","state"],

    correctAnswer: "state"

  },

  
  {

    question: "On systems where there are multiple operating system, the decision to load a particular one is done by _____________",

    options: ["process control block","file control block","boot loader","bootstrap"],

    correctAnswer: "boot loader"

  },

  
  {

    question: " In Unix, which system call creates the new process?",

    options: ["create","fork","new","none of the above"],

    correctAnswer: "fork"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which one of the following is the deadlock avoidance algorithm?",

    options: ["banker’s algorithm","round-robin algorithm","elevator algorithm","karn’s algorithm"],

    correctAnswer: "banker’s algorithm"

  },


  
  {

    question: "A problem encountered in multitasking when a process is perpetually denied necessary resources is called ____________",

    options: ["deadlock","starvation","inversion","aging"],

    correctAnswer: "starvation"

  },

  
  {

    question: "The request and release of resources are ___________",

    options: ["command line statements","interrupts","system calls","special programs"],

    correctAnswer: "system calls"

  },


  
  {

    question: "For a deadlock to arise, which of the following conditions must hold simultaneously?",

    options: ["Mutual exclusion","No preemption","Hold and wait","All of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "All of the mentioned"

  },

  
  {

    question: "______ is a unique tag, usually a number identifies the file within the file system.",

    options: ["File identifier","File name","File type","None of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "File identifier"

  },


  
  {

    question: "By using the specific system call, we can ____________",

    options: ["open the file","read the file","write into the file","all of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "all of the mentioned"

  },

  
  {

    question: "File type can be represented by ____________",

    options: ["file name","file extension","file identifier","none of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "file extension"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Which file is a sequence of bytes organized into blocks understandable by the system’s linker?",

    options: ["object file","source file","executable file","text file"],

    correctAnswer: " object file"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Mapping of file is managed by ____________",

    options: ["file metadata","page table","virtual memory","file system"],

    correctAnswer: "file metadata"

  },


  
  {

    question: "Mapping of network file system protocol to local file system is done by ____________",

    options: ["network file system","local file system","volume manager","remote mirror"],

    correctAnswer: "network file system"

  },

  
  {

    question: "The code segment that misuses its environment is called a _____________",

    options: ["internal thief","trojan horse","code stacker","none of the mentioned"],

    correctAnswer: "trojan horse"

  },


  
  {

    question: "The pattern that can be used to identify a virus is known as _____________",

    options: ["stealth","virus signature","armoured","multipartite"],

    correctAnswer: "virus signature"

  },

  
  {

    question: "Which one of the following is not an attack, but a search for vulnerabilities to attack?",

    options: ["denial of service","port scanning","memory access violation","dumpster diving"],

    correctAnswer: "port scanning"

  },
  
  ];
  
  
  
  // Variables to track quiz state
  
  let currentQuestionIndex = 0;
  
  let score = 0;
  
  let timeLeft = 900; // 15 minutes in seconds
  
  let timerInterval;
  
  let selectedQuestions = []; // Array to hold the selected questions
  
  
  
  // Function to start the quiz
  
  function startQuiz() {
  
    // Shuffle and select 20 random questions
  
    selectedQuestions = shuffleArray(quizQuestions).slice(0, 20);
  
  
  
    // Hide the start button and display the first question
  
    document.getElementById("start-button").style.display = "none";
  
    displayQuestion();
  
    startTimer();
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to shuffle an array (Fisher-Yates shuffle)
  
  function shuffleArray(array) {
  
    for (let i = array.length - 1; i > 0; i--) {
  
      const j = Math.floor(Math.random() * (i + 1));
  
      [array[i], array[j]] = [array[j], array[i]];
  
    }
  
    return array;
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to display a question and its options
  
  function displayQuestion() {
  
    const currentQuestion = selectedQuestions[currentQuestionIndex];
  
    const questionText = document.getElementById("question-text");
  
    const answerButtons = document.getElementById("answer-buttons");
  
  
  
    // Clear previous question and answer options
  
    questionText.innerHTML = "";
  
    answerButtons.innerHTML = "";
  
  
  
    // Display the current question
  
    questionText.innerHTML = currentQuestion.question;
  
  
  
    // Create answer buttons for each option
  
    currentQuestion.options.forEach(option => {
  
      const button = document.createElement("button");
  
      button.innerText = option;
  
      button.classList.add("answer-button");
  
      answerButtons.appendChild(button);
  
  
  
      // Add click event listener to check the answer
  
      button.addEventListener("click", function() {
  
        checkAnswer(option);
  
      });
  
    });
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to check the selected answer
  
  function checkAnswer(selectedOption) {
  
    const currentQuestion = selectedQuestions[currentQuestionIndex];
  
  
  
    // Check if the selected answer is correct
  
    if (selectedOption === currentQuestion.correctAnswer) {
  
      score++;
  
    }
  
  
  
    // Move to the next question or end the quiz if all questions are answered
  
    currentQuestionIndex++;
  
  
  
    if (currentQuestionIndex < selectedQuestions.length) {
  
      displayQuestion();
  
    } else {
  
      endQuiz();
  
    }
  
  }
  
  
  
  // function to start the timer
  
  function startTimer() {
  
    timerInterval = setInterval(function() {
  
      timeLeft--;
  
  
  
      // Calculate minutes and seconds
  
      const minutes = Math.floor(timeLeft / 60);
  
      const seconds = timeLeft % 60;
  
  
  
      // Update the timer text
  
      document.getElementById("minutes").textContent = minutes;
  
      document.getElementById("seconds").textContent = seconds < 10 ? "0" + seconds : seconds;
  
  
  
      // End the quiz if time runs out
  
      if (timeLeft <= 0) {
  
        endQuiz();
  
      }
  
    }, 1000);
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to end the quiz
  
  function endQuiz() {
  
    // Stop the timer
  
    clearInterval(timerInterval);
  
  
  
    // Calculate the score percentage
  
    const wrongAns = selectedQuestions.length - score;
  
  
  
    // Display the final score
  
    const questionContainer = document.getElementById("question-container");
  
    const resultsWindow = document.getElementById("results-window");
  
  
  
    let message = `
  
      <h2>Quiz Completed!</h2>
  
      <p id="question-text">Your Score       : ${score} out of ${selectedQuestions.length}</p>
  
      <p id="question-text">Correct Answers  : ${score}</p>
  
    `;
  
  
  
    // Check score and show modal if score is less than 5
  
    if (score < 5) {
  
      message += `<p id="question-text">Better luck next time!</p>`;
  
    } else {
  
      message += `<p id="question-text">Congratulations!</p>`;
  
    }
  
  
  
    resultsWindow.innerHTML = message;
  
    resultsWindow.classList.remove("hidden");
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Function to close the results modal
  
  function closeResultsModal() {
  
    const resultsWindow = document.getElementById("results-window");
  
    resultsWindow.classList.add("hidden");
  
  }
  
  
  
  // Add event listener to start the quiz when the start button is clicked
  
  document.getElementById("start-button").addEventListener("click", startQuiz);
  
  
  
  // Event listener to close modal when clicking outside
  
  window.addEventListener("click", function(event) {
  
    const resultsWindow = document.getElementById("results-window");
  
    if (event.target === resultsWindow) {
  
      closeResultsModal();
  
    }
  
  });